winnipegfreepress.com 2014-06-30

# Winnipeg Free Press - Breaking News, Sports, Manitoba, Canada

Privacy Policy

#### What is the Winnipeg Free Press’ (FP Canadian Newspapers Limited Partnership, or FPLP) privacy policy?

FPLP recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of personally identifiable information collected about our customers. This includes subscribers to and users of our services, purchasers of our products, advertisers (including those who advertise in classified ads), contest entrants, and visitors to our website. We adhere to fair information practices and limit the collection, use, and disclosure of personal information which is provided to us, to only that information which is necessary for our business purposes, and to provide services to you.

FPLP collects personal information when we provide our services and our products to our customers and to fulfill administrative functions associated with these services, for example to permit billing, delivery of our newspapers and for marketing and other customer relationship purposes. On occasion, we contract with others to provide these services to you and where we engage agents or contract with others to provide those services, we require those agents to demonstrate a similar commitment to maintaining your privacy.

We do not collect, use or disclose personal information about our customers without the consent of our customers, except where disclosure is permitted or required by law.

Whenever possible, FPLP will limit the use of information for the purpose for which it was collected and where we have identified a new use for that information, we will advise you and where reasonable and necessary secure your consent.

FPLP will retain personal information about customers for as long as is necessary for our business purposes and to comply with any applicable laws governing the retention of records.

When FPLP no longer requires the information for our business purposes or to meet those legal requirements, we will either destroy it or render it anonymous.

#### Links to other websites

Be aware that our websites may contain links to other websites provided and maintained exclusively by third parties not subject to FPLP Privacy Policy. Please review the privacy policies on any external websites to determine their information handling practices.

We place advertising on our websites that originate from third party advertisers. Even though these advertisements are embedded in our website, cookies may be assigned by the advertisers and not FPLP. FPLP does not control these cookies.

#### Access to Information Procedure

FPLP, on receipt of a written request by a customer and once that customer has verified that they are entitled to the personal information, will provide an opportunity to review any personal information that FPLP may have about that customer with the exception of any information gathered by its journalists and subject to exceptions set out in Section 9 of PIPEDA.

On receipt of written request and verification of the authority of the person to obtain the personal information, FPLP will make every effort to provide an opportunity for the customer to review the information within 30 days of the written request. If FPLP requires additional time to fulfill that request, the customer will be notified that a further period of time will be required to respond and a follow–up date will be given.

Before providing the information to a customer, FPLP will review that information and remove any sensitive commercial information about FPLP’s business practices and any personal information about identifiable third parties whom have not given consent for the information to be disclosed. If appropriate, the customer will be provided with a copy of the information, at the customer’s expense.

Where a customer believes that the personal information collected by FPLP is inaccurate, the customer may request FPLP make corrections to the personal information. FPLP may make the corrections requested. However, if there is a dispute between FPLP and the customer concerning the accuracy of the personal information collected, FPLP will note on the file that the customer disagrees with that personal information. If any third parties have been provided this information, FPLP will make all reasonable attempts to inform third parties of the correction.

#### Personal Information Complaints

If a customer wants to make a complaint about the manner in which FPLP has used, collected or disclosed personal information the complaint should be directed to the privacy officer. The customer should be assured that the complaint will be investigated and that if necessary the appropriate measures will be taken to correct FPLP’s information handling policies and practices. The complaint should be in writing and sent to 1355 Mountain Avenue, Winnipeg, Manitoba, R2X 3B6.

#### Any other questions?

If you have questions about our privacy practices, please contact us at FPLP at 1355 Mountain Avenue, Winnipeg, Manitoba, R2X 3B6.

This Policy may be updated and changed periodically. As changes are made to our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on this page. You are encouraged to review this page regularly for any changes.
